Privacy Policy
--------------

### The Law

We take reader privacy very seriously. Reader privacy enjoys special Constitutional protections under US law, and LibraryThing will not cooperate with US law enforcement unless compelled to do so. LibraryThing will not cooperate with non-US law enforcement unless compelled, or if we are convinced the law is at least as just, and applied as justly, as US standards. If you are using LibraryThing from a foreign country with an oppressive government, LibraryThing urges you not to put yourself at risk.

As of June 18, 2026, we have never received a National Security Letter, FISA order, or any other classified request for user information.

### No Sale of Personal Information

LibraryThing will not sell or give personally-identifiable information to any third party. This would be evil, and we are not evil. Yes, [still](https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/gadgets-and-tech/news/google-dont-be-evil-code-conduct-removed-alphabet-a8361276.html).

There is one exception to this rule, described below (see Reviews under Sharing and Transfer of Information). Review sharing is entirely optional and member-controlled.

We reserve and currently exercise the right to sell or give away anonymous or aggregate information.

See Sharing and Transfer of Information, below, for more on this topic.

### Emails from LibraryThing

LibraryThing membership requires an email address.

LibraryThing respects your inbox. We do not sell your email address to authors, publishers, marketing companies, or anyone else.

By default, most new members who provide their email address are subscribed to our "State of the Thing" newsletter. Members who join from the EEA after May 25, 2018 are not subscribed automatically, and will have to consent explicitly to receive the State of the Thing.

By default, members who provide their email address receive private messages by email. This can be disabled in the [Privacy Center](https://www.librarything.com/settings/privacy). LibraryThing reserves the right to send profile-comment emails for GDPR-exempt system notifications, and customer support.

See LibraryThing Early Reviewers, below, for terms surrounding this optional program.

### Member Privacy Center

All LibraryThing members have access to their own Member [Privacy Center](https://www.librarything.com/settings/privacy), where they can see and then update:

*   Subscription settings for different types of LibraryThing emails
*   Review-sharing preferences
*   EEA or non-EEA residency
*   Display preferences for name, location and other non-required fields
*   Application-sharing preferences, such as to Facebook and Twitter
*   Export and download account data (incomplete as of June 8, 2018)
*   Disable or delete your account

### How to Delete Your Data

LibraryThing members have full control over deleting their accounts and personal data.

#### To permanently delete your account and associated data:

1.  Go to your [Account Settings](https://www.librarything.com/settings/account).
2.  Scroll to the bottom of the page, under the **“Big Steps”** section, and click **Delete Account**.
3.  You’ll be prompted to confirm your password.
4.  After confirming, you’ll be taken to the **Delete Account** page, where you can review and complete the process.

#### On the Delete Account page, you’ll see information about what deletion means:

*   Your account and all personal data will be permanently deleted and cannot be restored.
*   Your books, reviews, ratings, and library data will be removed.
*   Contributions to shared community resources, such as book covers or Common Knowledge entries, are retained.
*   If you use TinyCat, your catalog will be disabled.
*   You can choose whether to keep, anonymize, or delete your Talk posts and private messages.

Before deleting your account, you have the option to [export your books](https://www.librarything.com/export) and [download your personal data](https://www.librarything.com/settings/export).

If you need assistance or prefer to request deletion manually, you can contact us at [info@librarything.com](mailto:info@librarything.com).

### Private Libraries

LibraryThing allows "private" libraries—libraries that others can't see. We cannot give an absolute 100% guarantee of privacy. After all, even Amazon had a day when all their "anonymous" reviewers were exposed by mistake. If the public disclosure of your library would really damage you, by all means don't post it online.

LibraryThing has a "private books" feature, marked as a "beta" feature. It is not fully functional, and does not guarantee security.

### Mobile Apps (Android and iOS)

#### Privacy Policy

This section covers the policies for the following apps: LibraryThing, LibAnywhere, FCPL Mobile, LINKcat, MtLaurelLib, and Unisa Library. These services are provided to the user as is.

This page is used to inform website visitors regarding our policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use our Services.

If you choose to use our Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation with this policy. The Personal Information that LibraryThing collects are used for providing and improving the Service. LibraryThing will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Information Collection and Use

For a better experience while using our Service, LibraryThing may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to location information and access to pictures/camera on your device. The information that LibraryThing requests is retained on your device and is not collected by LibraryThing in any way, except if specifically uploaded by you (example: book cover photos uploaded to your books).

#### Log Data

LibraryThing wants to inform you that whenever you use our Services, in case of an error in the apps we collect data and information which is transmitted directly to our server in the form of Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your devices's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, operating system version, configuration of the app when utilising the Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and possibly other anonymous statistics.

#### Cookies

Cookies are files with small amount of data that is commonly used an anonymous unique identifier. These are sent to your browser from the website that you visit and are stored on your devices's internal memory.

LibraryThing services may use "cookies" to provide automatic sign-in for certain features (example: the LibraryThing app). You have the option to set up your device to accept or refuse these cookies, and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.

#### Security

LibraryThing values your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and LibraryThing cannot guarantee its absolute security.

#### Links to Other Sites

This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by LibraryThing. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.

#### Children's Privacy

See the [COPPA section](#coppa).

#### Changes to This App Privacy Policy

LibraryThing may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. You are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. LibraryThing will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. These changes are effective immediately, after they are posted on this page.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions about LibraryThing's App Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us.

### Social Apps

LibraryThing allows members to connect to various apps, like Facebook and Twitter, that require application authorization. We will not use this for any purpose other than explicitly agreed to. The data we collect from these apps is used only for authentication purposes, and to post to the services as directed. It is not displayed, transferred, or shared in any way.

LibraryThing does not store any information for Facebook and Twitter except the keys necessary to perform API requests. In other words, all that stuff that Facebook gave companies like Cambridge Analytics, and which they misused, we have never stored and don't store now. We reserve the right to store your Facebook "name."

### As Is

We work hard to keep LibraryThing useful, accurate, and online, but we offer it "as is" and "as available." We don't make formal warranties: we can't guarantee the site will always be up, error-free, or exactly what you need, and we don't warrant that book data, recommendations, covers, or other content are perfectly accurate. We do try, though—and we love it when you help us fix things.

### The Limits of Our Liability

LibraryThing is made by a small company, offered to you in good faith. We can't promise perfection. To the fullest extent the law allows, LibraryThing and its staff won't be liable for indirect, incidental, or consequential damages arising from your use of—or inability to use—the site, such as lost data, lost profits, or a catalog gone sideways.

If, despite all this, we are ever found liable for something, our total liability to you is limited to the amount you paid us in the previous twelve months, or $100 if you haven't paid us anything. Some places don't allow these limits, in which case they apply to you only as far as the law there permits.

### Covering Our Backs

If something you post or do on LibraryThing lands us in a dispute with someone else—say, you post something that wasn't yours to post, or you break these terms or the law—you agree to cover the reasonable costs we run into as a result, including reasonable legal fees. We'll let you know promptly if this ever comes up, and honestly we'd much rather sort it out together than ever need this paragraph.

### Governing Law and Disputes

LibraryThing is a Maine company. These terms, and any dispute about them or about your use of LibraryThing, are governed by the laws of the State of Maine and applicable U.S. federal law, without regard to conflict-of-laws rules. If a dispute can't be worked out in a friendly way—and we really will try first—it belongs in the state or federal courts located in Portland, Maine, and you agree to that.

This general rule sits alongside the more specific terms in [Automated Access, Scraping, and Data Use](#automated-access), above, which continue to govern that section. And while we're here: we're not fans of forcing anyone into mandatory arbitration or stripping away the right to a day in court, so we don't.

### Odds and Ends

A few standard housekeeping points, kept short:

*   **Severability.** If a court decides any part of these terms doesn't hold up, the rest stays in force.
*   **The whole deal.** These terms—together with the policies they link to, like the [Community Rules](#community-rules) and [Privacy Policy](#privacy-policy)—are the complete agreement between you and LibraryThing about using the site.
*   **Waiver.** If we don't enforce a rule right away, that doesn't mean we've given it up.
*   **Assignment.** You can't hand your rights under these terms to someone else, but we may transfer ours—for instance, if the company is ever sold—as long as the new owner honors them.

### We Take It All Back

These terms and conditions are subject to the usual change-at-any-time rule that websites put on their terms and conditions and which seem so unfair. ("What, I have to submit a DNA sample?") We have edited them as new situations have come up, but we promise not to change any of the core principles, particularly with regard to sale of information, copyright and death rays. We promise to make all changes openly, with tracking and with the opportunity for users to withdraw their accounts.

BY USING LIBRARYTHING.COM DIRECTLY OR THROUGH A MEDIUM LIKE A COMPUTER WITH A KEYBOARD AND MAYBE A MOUSE ATTACHED YOU AGREE TO TAKE THESE IMPORTANT AND CONSEQUENTIAL TERMS OF USE SERIOUSLY EVEN THOUGH, OR EVEN BECAUSE, WE HAVE ONLY ONE SENTENCE AT THE END IN CAPITAL LETTERS.
